The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Seventh Episode
The Swan
Hey, Garigori!
Hello, chamberlain! I'm coming!
Greetings, great keeper of time!
How's it going?
Bad, damn it!
Why are you so nervous, Garigori?
Because my only daughter Mary
has disappeared!
What can I do? Poor me!
- Mary has disappeared?!
- She's nowhere to be found! Poor Mary!
Good!
We evil spirits
wish Hecate...
...a very happy birthday!
Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to Hecate,
happy birthday to you!
Many thanks, friends!
- Do you have presents for her?
- Of course!
A face lotion,
made with the blood
of snake and lizard.
Yes, my lord!
If your daughter Hecate...
...rubs her face
with it every day,
she will become meaner
and prettier.
An elixir of vulture tears...
...in the horn of a goat
blind in one eye.
- Is this yours?
- Yes! One drop in her eyes...
...will give her sight
so sharp...
...who will read
the minds of men!
Idiots!
Take back your trash!
For my daughter
I only want one thing:
a heart that will make her become
a good... witch!
- Sapphire's blue one?
- Exactly!
Prince Sapphire,
even though she is a girl,
also has the heart of a boy!
When I take that heart away from her and
transplant it into Hecate's chest,
I will make my daughter
a great witch!
You, swan!
Will this be the animal
that will bring me Prince Sapphire!
Go to Earth, cursed swan!
So, tell me: have you found Mary?
Still no trace, Your Highness.
Then go back to scour the kingdom
in search of her!
Yes, Your Highness!
I hear a strange sound...!
It's a swan! It seems injured
Don't be afraid,
I don't want to hurt you.
No, don't run away!
Garigori! Catch that swan
that fell behind you!
What?! How do you expect me
to start thinking about a swan...
...with all the worries
that I have?!
But Garigori!
I'm afraid its wound will
get worse if it keeps flying!
Don't be afraid, I'll take care of it!
Gotcha!
Come! I'll nurse you back to
health, beautiful little swan!
Sapphire!
I thought
someone was calling me!
- I'm here!
- Ah, it's you, Tink!
What happened to that swan?
It's injured
and I caught it to treat it.
No! Sapphire, let go of
that swan! Leave it alone!
- And why is that?
- Because it is not a normal swan.
I feel that that animal
comes from the devil's court.
- The devil?!
- Yes, but I will break the spell.
...with my angel feather.
There! Did you see?
Is it true that you are
not a normal swan?
Look, it is trying to
tell me something.
It seems it wants to ask for help!
It says it is a girl kidnapped by
Mephisto and transformed into a swan.
Perhaps I know who you are! You
are Mary, Garigori's daughter, right?
Now this is a surprise! That is
why Mary is nowhere to be found!
We should inform Garigori of
what happened to his daughter.
Mary! Mary! My poor
daughter! Where did you go?
Garigori, we have
found your daughter!
- Really? And where is she?
- Right before your eyes!
She was transformed
into a swan by Mephisto!
My daughter! Dear Mary,
what happened to you?
My poor daughter! What
have they done to you?!
You were the
consolation of my life!
Poor, little dear! Mary! Mary!
- Did you hear?
- Opal, little horse, come here!
- No!
- Leave me alone! I will teach Mephisto a lesson!
But don't you understand?!
This is one of his traps!
Mary, speak, my little
girl! Tell me something!
Opal! Opal!
Listen, Opal...
Opal! Go, Opal! To the
field of the black lily!
Hey! Hey, Opal!
Where are you going? Stop!
You are going in the wrong
direction! You have to go the other way!
Stop! Opal!
But where could he be taking me?
What happened to me? Where am I?
I'm sorry, Sapphire, I
was forced to tie you up.
- I didn't want you to go.
- How dare you stand in my way?
I will never forgive you!
You will stay in this little church
until I have driven out Mephisto.
Here you are safe, because
the devil will be afraid to enter.
You can't do such a thing! You
won't be able to defeat Mephisto!
Yes I can! You forget that
I have an angel's feather.
- Let me come with you, Tink!
- No way!
- My poor daughter is dead!
- What?!
Her body is already cold!
My feather will restore her to life.
- It's useless!
- Why didn't it work?
Mephisto has taken Mary back!
He has imprisoned her
soul in a magic sphere.
To get her back, that sphere must
be exposed to the morning light.
Untie me and I will get that
sphere! Damn it, he's already gone!
Come back, Tink! Wait!
What is happening?
Help! The roof is collapsing!
- Where did His Highness go?
- Opal!
I bet it's Sapphire...!
Stop, Sapphire! Don't go!
Mephisto is doing this on purpose to
make you fall into a trap! You mustn't!
Get out of the way or you'll be trampled!
You asked for it!
Know that the Prince of
Silverland is not afraid of any devil.
And now excuse me,
but I'll take your feather.
You're doing a foolish thing! What
will happen if Mephisto captures you?
Silverland will fall into the
hands of the evil bandits...
...should you be killed!
Well, well!
My plan is succeeding!
Are you happy, Hecate?
Sapphire is falling into my net!
I can't bring myself to
be happy. I don't feel well.
Are you really not feeling well?
Then you can take a little
poison, or... Oh, I've got it!
The devils! Damn it!
Look at them there! They are
all drunk! Now I'll handle this!
Dance!
Sapphire wants to fight Mephisto
alone, but he won't make it!
The devil is far
stronger than him!
I must try to free
myself so I can help him!
You'll have to deal with me, Mephisto!
It's fantastic!
Come!
My little Hecate, do you know that
you are about to become a great witch?
You don't need to worry, I
will always be close to you!
You'll see, I will make you happy!
For you I would do anything!
I would even fight
against Heaven!
But if you did that, the Lord would
turn you to ashes as punishment!
I wouldn't care about
being turned to ashes...
...for my dear, little Hecate!
Dad!
So hot...! That crater is
the entrance to Mephisto's lair.
Are you feeling better
now that you've had fun?
Yes! It had been a long
time since I had this much fun!
Hail, Mephisto!
I'm sure you'll like
it! Open the box!
I wonder what's there...!
Oh, what a beautiful cake!
Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you!
I'm so happy! So, let's hear:
how old are you today, Hecate?
- 13, Dad!
- Devils, I need 13 candles!
How wonderful, Dad!
Come on, blow out the
candles, daughter! Blow!
No! No! Why don't you put
out the fire with your magic?
Hail Mephisto!
The hellfire is too strong
for this little breeze.
Hail Mephisto!
Eat the fire of the candles
for me, fire-eating bird!
You're not there yet! Give it your all!
I want rain! Hail Mephisto!
It seems a bit too little to
put out a fire, don't you think?
Downpour!
Now it's too much! The
birthday cake will melt!
Poor me,
I can't do anything right!
Come on, come on,
daughter! It's not that bad.
I know anyway that
everything I do is done badly!
Don't be discouraged,
daughter, but keep trying...
...until things
go well for you!
Ehi, Mephisto!
I smell a human!
Really?
Yeah, seems like it to me too
This means that Sapphire
has finally arrived!
Get ready, Hecate!
Go Mephisto!
You're trapped now, Sapphire!
I want to stay as I am, Dad!
I don't want you to
give me Sapphire's heart!
- Please, Dad!
- Don't be foolish!
- Lie down here for the operation!
- No, Dad! I don't want to!
Now it's between us,
Prince! You won't escape!
But where is he? He was
just here! I know he was here!
Watch out!
This is an angel's feather!
Damn you!
- I'm taking the magic sphere!
- No!
- I want it, Mephisto!
- You'll have to fight for it!
Come, Hecate!
No, she stays here!
Move, Hecate! Damn Sapphire,
what do you intend to do?
If you hurt her, I will kill you!
I will send your daughter up there
only if you give me the magic sphere!
- How dare you?
- Look, I have the feather!
- You'd better make a deal!
- Damn that feather!
Alright, I'll accept the exchange! But
aren't you ashamed of blackmailing me?
What are you babbling about, Mephisto?
You should be ashamed, rather,
for having transformed
sweet Mary into a swan!
Alright, you won this time!
Damn the feather!
Take the magic sphere!
Good!
Faster, friends! Hurry up!
Damn this tooth!
Damn it!
- Picchio, can you give me a hand?
- I'm coming!
Thank you, you were very kind!
Don't mention it, it was a pleasure!
And besides, I'm crazy about the rope!
I wasn't calling you, but some
bird to get a ride.
What do you mean? That I'm not
strong enough to give you a lift?
Well, even though I'm small,
I think I weigh enough for you.
No nonsense! Hang on!
Wow! I didn't think
you were so strong!
The feather! Whirlwind,
blow that feather away!
Now Sapphire
will no longer be able to resist me!
Hecate! Hecate!
Hecate, where are you?
Let me hide among you.
Hecate, where have you hidden?
You can't fool me! I see that there
is one swan too many among you.
Hecate, I know you have
transformed into a swan!
Turn back to normal
and don't make me angry!
No, dad! I don't want to!
Don't be foolish and remember
that you are the daughter of Mephisto!
I thought you cared about
making me happy, dad.
Too bad for you!
No, let go of me, dad!
I don't want to! Please!
Get over there!
What?! Is dawn already breaking?
Damn it! How time has flown
tonight!
Come on, try again!
I'm a bit hoarse,
I can't do it.
The rooster's crow,
you can do it even better!
Alright, now I'll try to do it
a bit better! Let's see...
- I did it!
- Still, it doesn't convince me!
There are still stars in the sky.
This rooster suffers from insomnia!
Damned beast, it's still night!
Cut it out!
I'm falling!
What the dev...! It's an angel! Help!
An angel on me! Help!
Get him off me! Help!
An angel has latched onto me!
I can't shake him off!
He's going to kill me!
Father, give him that sphere right now!
Hurry up!
I'll give it to you, poisonous angel!
Just go away!
- Sapphire! - He almost drowned
to get the magic sphere!
Sapphire, wake up!
Sapphire, it's me: Tink!
- And what are you doing here?
- Help me! I can't swim!
- The sphere is at the bottom of the lake!
- I'm going to get it now!
We must expose it
to the rising morning sun,
thus the swan's spell
will be broken.
Look, the sun is about to rise!
Right in that direction!
What a miracle!
But it's Mary!
- My little girl! Mary!
- Dear Papa!
- My daughter!
- Papa!
Look, Tink:
there is another swan flying!
Yes, I see it, but... That is
Hecate, the daughter of Mephisto!
I wonder why she is accompanying us...
I think she would gladly make
friends with us,
if she could forget
whose daughter she is.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP